<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://blog.moutella.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://blog.moutella.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-02-09T01:54:45+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.moutella.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Moutella Devlogs</title><subtitle>Logging my daily progress with coding interview university</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Just take it a day at a time 🙂</title><link href="https://blog.moutella.com/objectives/learning/coding-interview-university/2022/02/09/first-day.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Just take it a day at a time 🙂" /><published>2022-02-09T00:51:34+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-09T00:51:34+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.moutella.com/objectives/learning/coding-interview-university/2022/02/09/first-day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.moutella.com/objectives/learning/coding-interview-university/2022/02/09/first-day.html"><![CDATA[<p>I just saw the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iOq5kSKqeR4">first video</a> of the <a href="https://github.com/moutella/coding-interview-university">coding-interview-university</a>, where a Harvard student explains basic asymptotic notation, like what does O(n), O(1), O(n^2) means and so on, which is kind of a breeze for anyone who has taken a few computer science classes. However, I do admit that I had forgotten what does Ω(n) means, and what does Θ(n) means, and that made me be humble, because I realized that yes, there is a lot of knowledge I don’t know.</p>

<p>I decided to also watch the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V6mKVRU1evU">second video</a> in the asymptotic notation part of the study, and apart from the quick explanation about O(n log n), everything is pretty basic for someone who has had a algorithm analysis class in college, which I did. I hope I don’t feel this throughout the entire journey, otherwise I shall have to pick something else to use as the path for my studies.</p>

<p>This may be a little unfair with the repository, which is filled with good information about computer science, interviews, resumes and everything to help someone find themselves a career in software engineering, and I do realize the author does indeed say that he has not studied computer science in college, so maybe I do need something else. Well, I’ll stick to the program at least for a week before jumping ship. Now, it’s time to go back to do a few Hackerrank challenges</p>

<p>Thank you for reading!</p>]]></content><author><name>John Moutella</name></author><category term="objectives" /><category term="learning" /><category term="coding-interview-university" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I just saw the first video of the coding-interview-university, where a Harvard student explains basic asymptotic notation, like what does O(n), O(1), O(n^2) means and so on, which is kind of a breeze for anyone who has taken a few computer science classes. However, I do admit that I had forgotten what does Ω(n) means, and what does Θ(n) means, and that made me be humble, because I realized that yes, there is a lot of knowledge I don’t know.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Better coder, better me</title><link href="https://blog.moutella.com/objectives/2022/02/08/my-first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Better coder, better me" /><published>2022-02-08T01:23:30+00:00</published><updated>2022-02-08T01:23:30+00:00</updated><id>https://blog.moutella.com/objectives/2022/02/08/my-first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.moutella.com/objectives/2022/02/08/my-first-post.html"><![CDATA[<p>A few months after graduating, I have realized that I don’t really know a lot of stuff that I should, and that there are thousands of improvementes that I can work on.</p>

<p>Because of that, I’ve decided that it is time to start re-learning a lot of basic computer science, while also starting to get deeper knowledge about cloud computing. For the CS part, I’ll be doing <a href="https://github.com/moutella/coding-interview-university">coding-interview-university</a> alongside with <a href="https://www.hackerrank.com/moutella">hackerrank</a>. For the cloud Stuff, I haven’t decided my path yet. I currently work with AWS, using a lot of Lambda, Step Functions and API Gateway, however, I know that is only the tip of the iceberg.</p>

<p>The language I will be using for the most part will be Python, since I already use it a lot, however, sometimes I may challenge myself to work with C, just to check if I still am able to do low-level pointer stuff when messing with data-structures.</p>

<p>At the same time I’m doing this, I will write these blog posts in English, because I believe it’s going to improve my ability to write and read in english. I also need to find a way to improve my speaking skills, but that is a problem for later</p>

<p>I won’t be posting everyday, but I will definitely try to post at least twice a week.</p>

<p>Thank you for reading!</p>]]></content><author><name>John Moutella</name></author><category term="objectives" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few months after graduating, I have realized that I don’t really know a lot of stuff that I should, and that there are thousands of improvementes that I can work on. Because of that, I’ve decided that it is time to start re-learning a lot of basic computer science, while also starting to get deeper knowledge about cloud computing. For the CS part, I’ll be doing coding-interview-university alongside with hackerrank. For the cloud Stuff, I haven’t decided my path yet. I currently work with AWS, using a lot of Lambda, Step Functions and API Gateway, however, I know that is only the tip of the iceberg. The language I will be using for the most part will be Python, since I already use it a lot, however, sometimes I may challenge myself to work with C, just to check if I still am able to do low-level pointer stuff when messing with data-structures. At the same time I’m doing this, I will write these blog posts in English, because I believe it’s going to improve my ability to write and read in english. I also need to find a way to improve my speaking skills, but that is a problem for later I won’t be posting everyday, but I will definitely try to post at least twice a week. Thank you for reading!]]></summary></entry></feed>